{"qu1":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>1 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">In a hugely popular singing reality show, every day, the best performer of the day was conferred with the title of &lsquo;Leader of the Day&rsquo; and was given a cash prize of Rs.10001. On the first of August 2017, if the title was jointly awarded to 17 singers and the cash prize was equally shared by all of them, the prize amount received by each singer was a<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>natural number.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>non-terminating recurring decimal.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>non-terminating non-recurring decimal.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>terminating decimal.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu2":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>1 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Find the percentage change in the volume of a cone, if the radius of its base is decreased by 20% and its height is increased by 50%.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>4% decrease\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>6% decrease\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>4% increase\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>6% increase\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu3":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>A group of workers in a puppet manufacturing company was assigned the task of making 395 puppets. Each worker in the group works at a constant rate and makes five puppets per hour. At the end of the first hour, some of the workers were reassigned to another task; at the end of the second hour, the same number of the remaining workers were also reassigned to another task, and a similar reassignment occurred at the end of every hour till the task was complete. If the entire task was completed in 4 hours and 20 minutes, how many puppets were finished in the first three hours?\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"315","CORRECT_ANSWER":"315","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu4":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b><\/b>Find the total number of steps visible at any point of time on the escalator.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>40\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>48\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>60\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>56\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"3685","EASSY_DETAILS":"<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"> <b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>4 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>5<\/i><i>: <\/i>Answer the questions on the basis of the information given below.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">Raju is walking down an escalator (a moving staircase) which is moving down. From the top, he takes 20 steps to reach the bottom, while Rajat, who walks twice as fast as Raju, takes 30 steps from the top to reach the bottom.<i><b>\n<\/b><\/i><\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","ESSAY_NAME":"D-X) Test name AIMCAT1815"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":"","ESSAY_NAME":""},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu5":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b><\/b>Find the number of steps that Rajesh, a friend of Raju, would take to reach the bottom, if he starts from the top and walks half as fast as Raju.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>10\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>12\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>16\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>18\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"3685","EASSY_DETAILS":"<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"> <b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>4 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>5<\/i><i>: <\/i>Answer the questions on the basis of the information given below.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">Raju is walking down an escalator (a moving staircase) which is moving down. From the top, he takes 20 steps to reach the bottom, while Rajat, who walks twice as fast as Raju, takes 30 steps from the top to reach the bottom.<i><b>\n<\/b><\/i><\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","ESSAY_NAME":"D-X) Test name AIMCAT1815"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":"","ESSAY_NAME":""},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu6":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Which of the following gives the product of all the positive numbers which differ from their reciprocal by 3?\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='18' Height= '17' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAARCAYAAADQWvz5AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHvSURBVDhPhZI9aFpRGIavCOles7UFJ0EQQdJVRQfBIVqoSRA3szSCci2tODnEZEtd0iHdFEXxJ8ZEhwYXJyebpJPgoouDGBEHf\/DvrflyEpM09\/rAx\/X9znce9Z7DYQWlUgkejwd+v1+0VopcLhfC4TA6nY5oiYpmsxkMBgMajQbrCCMqqlarMBqNJFyFqCgajcLpdLIkjqiI53mEQiGWgFqtht1dJ9RqNTY2PuLg8BDj8ZjWREVmsxmVSoU+1+t1rMveYm3tDdxuN7ZsNnAch81NK60LirrdLvR6Pfr9PuVt22faeHPzl\/Idfp+Pen+uroVFxWIRFouFJeAsm8XR0Q+W7rk4z5Eonc4Ii4LBIAKBAEuvs7O9RaL27e1SlM\/nMZ1OWQLsdjuyi18hRPb0lCTfvvsoc+VyGVqtlpoPJzQcDqHT6dBsNim\/5NfJCc1brZ8wn8+pxyUSCSSTSSiVSshkMkwmEzpmk8lEAy852N8nyZe9Pda55\/GvxeNxGojFYigUCq9exK9eL80cH\/9knSWPorv3I5fLoVAo4HA46FY\/JZ1KkoTnvRgMBmi322i1WlSj0ej5qUUiERqWSqV0AR+YLb7kw\/t3tCaRSOj5tFKp9P\/Hr1KpoNFoWFpyefkbuVwOmUxmsTH1rHq9Hv4BfPL75UVO37sAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>2\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>3\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>None of the above\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu7":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">As shown in the figure below, ABC is a triangle, such that AB = 14 cm, BC = 13 cm and AC = 15 cm. If AD and BE are angle bisectors, intersecting the altitude CE, drawn to side AB, at X and Y respectively, and the measure (in cm) of XY is <i>m<\/i>, find the value of 42<em>m<\/em>. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhrgDBAPcAAP\/\/\/2lpaSMjI8PDw6enp4mJiUdHR93d3QAAAPf39wwMDLe3t5+fn0BAQDAwMM\/Pz6+vr1BQUEhISCAgIN\/f34+Pj3BwcOfn53h4eIeHh9fX1ygoKJeXl2hoaL+\/vxgYGDg4OMfHx2BgYO\/v71hYWH9\/f5WVlTo6OhsbGyEhIYiIiC0tLRYWFj8\/P6CgoGdnZwYGBn19fR8fHz4+PoODgw0NDQMDA09PTwEBAWNjY2FhYQ4ODh0dHWVlZZKSki8vLzIyMjk5OQcHBwQEBG1tbYaGhsHBwRMTExAQEHt7exwcHGtra+Dg4CIiInNzc6ioqAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAArgDBAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhz6twpM4AAnkBnChAwIKjRlgQKFAhwtGlKAwcOIHBKleQAAwINEKjK9WMABGAR\/OxKVuPUgQiKll1LMSnBAEzZyoUo4ABBqXbn6t3Lt6\/fv4BvJghMeGACBQsKE2aAoIHiwA4QOHjw2C+ECAguV+47eerkzXo1T9UMWq6ExGcnUCi99oEDgWcrWGBdNgIE2AITTLhAm6trtANl965qG3ju3cObXpgwGPdADBmSH7VQgeBZgcubS9+Z3XpB6tt5gvX3TrB7eJzmjRMcf96m8ILXB2rY0N6mbt7wDxavP\/N9foO\/8RfTfQfFR9B+ArrEQQcIGThQgAm29FmBCU0YoUqkUYhQhheiZKFBDhL0YYckcQiiQiaSKFIDHigUooiUqTgShA0u5J+MICFYo0IE4vgRjTsqdKOPG+kYZEI9EqnRBR809GJBGWCg5EbsudhQelNWhGVCT35XXZYWVWnllcyBSdGWXD4kppkODTnmlU2yCVGSDHVpkJFyCjnbQ3YWBGSeCNFZZ0R4AlrQghH16edrhlYYI58SsdjoQSkOGlGljY7o5ESaGorpQooa9KmcIIQwUagGdf8q558OoVoQAyJMKlChm04k6KqMnlqRm2zSWqutyAFKwQQWuWoQr1muCZGxBY3wgXZmornsRcoqWS2kFknro7bYhvklmFFixKxB3JJ4q0TjGkTCVlkim2hGrKp4Lroa+Xqhu+\/Cm6uPqtJb720+jppvRgLz16+\/Gh1cX8HTbsRweKVylK6jKsZb0cQbRqCivbpyNG9YYalVmsUXe4QsAnklx3HHHgcLX8q9zfcRxgnxirJ01xb7UQIfjAAiyGOBVm7JH61583A56\/zRlkfTNjTRRX8LG8yllVBCSDQrhCXIYLH72LwZZa2QCCach6+4IY1wAgrhgR02SAtssMDKip3\/jXZHCXQgAW8kV7aBBiOJTVAIDnBwIMC9Pay0RhmAADhBHjg2nMJvZ6QBCFIeRDlgii9uEQMRZ9zb5ndXNIIEIvisEOl89b0RxnEnxlDnetFduUR57\/3QB\/hV5vrrExFuOER282X77Q81\/vicLhcm80muXp75RMXPlXRHqIJuakVu6\/W0xA2dnjpG0Cl2PfYMxb5kmYF9Dz6SIuhOpdRccY1VQVar9CThDHjkvk5NM0j3ZoaQEjgOJOfbSQALUj30FeRyVwvJ7xRINcM0D3qvcsD2RHI8nHANZg10IAAugDpoSXBfVFngQFTDkrMswAGyM0kHbaJCANBOYgmIX+9M\/zJBD1YQAKzziGT6t5Ig1kSFN9xICRCwPAxpbC4pUMFKICi4ihhRJyFYAQk+gIHVmIQBGgRAFSmSRJwU5wIZYEELvAYSEoqgOWOkyN9as68JuGCLXfzIC2MoRpiEMCcICgEIsJOBCTSAASbkng7\/45IB7uQFMCiBF8sHORF8oANNDJ4DiMhIl\/zRJhaIQQkMyQAZeLFZHNgACBA5EQNmUj2NvOBRzOMBSyZycJbE5EMg+CYAEOBoUmGjSMJVlfMJ4H4CScEMVMlKhXAgjL0EQAHGIgBhiuR\/NHEfAthFgPuFIJevHKEEOnDLTgpEAEpBpkkSWBNKNuSXUyPICFK5yikE0AAEEFDfrwYilRpek31GceRADLCUAiDkmzWwAQJs0ALV7XMgQ1kJO\/9l8kepBA0hNwALDnLgUEu9xQDoVMmwjiLQtxhUITqwwQ540IMPiGCD0RwAyqQispPM0JN7ikgATnqQy2VgBC0CQAJAtwEOdPREBKmmQKapkh7ChIUS2SlCnglTgmigAy6tKiyPmVR1yhBxOimjVAtCQnIuZKggKOpR46gvoFwxIfp0yFWzCsuZSCqsT8TICOJ3VIegdQM++AECgFDOlpTxJG81iCA5WRENBAEHCBDC8GiS2JIIMiMYOCDBaoCAIbAgAzuEyWFJctMHgiA6HCECAohAAQx8gAR8fEllReLUg1CVgAMhgAQmAFqYIMompcXOOAt7EQe19rWxTUlJeYj\/QohAQG4ieZJueRvak3xyJB2YLET2GoG+ihAhx4WtSpY7EmwKhH8lCdV0M3DKklwXgfRjSAIy297oQqS1E5CANUHiLOKeBJsaaABqTTKuBeCxvlGLyUQrAE0MnqmQ+v2nf0kiUBJaYMJCxIiBuYhgjUz0I9V7bnIJvCQI7\/ci5m1ZdQ3CXe+SmCMbzmORwJoSu6HXJWwdoYk1UluO8I5H9IVJjgeyYV1eJLgXGVWAB\/ySIZeHns2cSI8z0i8Ga7UlTlYsOCmCZDLmlawSuDBNsnyQeTITwwQZLacelWboHpEl37xkOClmksixWATdvQmZF2LmejZEzRAxUgg2wNg3\/8MkzkZeHZtPSJD5gmDFM9nzQ\/rMABf7kgQlQZBPeSLpiMT5pQchr0QglIHZOtg+RDUqA3MKkuyKEwNoFvJO5grq40A6I9khgJuD0umL\/FXV722IBYogAhJY2oNHobURerY0GBzhBlaLtrSnTe1qW\/va2M621ZCg7W57+9vaTsINlACDJXyECU1wArjXze52u\/vd8J72Ep4gq3rb+974ZgvXasppkJ0YJ78EC0\/Nkhd4GqVp2wwKU885cHGlrNdhS1k3eZ0yqUgsLwOIC8XJs5OrRBdkXqUgx3Uycaw9nN8ArDjEK+Jxkw\/03zSUeMh9yE9\/nurhP6Q5bFCOk4UDQB0AGg+bv4+y76MUICwNz7fSl870pjv96VCPOgACAgA7\" style=\"width: 174px; height: 193px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"49","CORRECT_ANSWER":"49","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu8":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>15<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">If <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">are positive real numbers such that <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">= 6, find the minimum value of <\/span><em style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a<\/em><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + <\/span><em style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b<\/em><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>18\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>20\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>26\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>None of the above\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu9":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>15<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Akash, Bilal and Chintu were supposed to divide a certain amount, N, among themselves in the ratio 1 : 2 : 3 respectively. Instead, they erroneously divided the amount in the ratio 4 : 3 : 2 respectivley. If in the process, Akash gained Rs. 2000, find N.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Rs. 4500\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Rs. 6300\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Rs. 7200\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Rs. 9600\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu10":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>15<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Find the product of the roots of the equation (2<em>x<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + 13) (<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&minus; 3) + (2<em>x<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + 13) (<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&minus; 5) = 0.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>26\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9999999'> \u221226 \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>39\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9999999'> \u221239 \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu11":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>15<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">A retailer selling mangoes offered a flat discount of 10% on his marked price. Further, owing to persistent bargaining by a customer, he offered <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">mangoes free for every 12 mangoes purchased by the customer and still made an overall profit of 20% in the transaction. Find the value of <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">, if the mangoes were marked at <\/span><img src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADIAAAAhCAYAAACbffiEAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAbiSURBVFhH1VgJTFVXEH0gS6ssFTAiyhIBsZJoKy3KorSpohWXWGMDtMomRYFEBbUWqrggYiq7BWwr1gqWHUxAQdkKttLKVuCrgGj9KiCo8I0kyja9d959fJZvNYVP4klu\/psz8+978+7cmbmPgwmAqL4etm\/fDl5eXoMjIyODaccHcnektvZvMNDXBwUFBdiwYQO4ubmBpqYmTJo0CY6GHmNWY4dcHZF0dYG21lTgOA5ycy8wFuDWrSYwMjJEvqKikrFjg1wdqbj2Fz7s+wstGCNFwN6vUTdeqyJXR3p6evDtNzQ2MkaKLe7u6MiPP51izNgwIZt9JJqaGkFdTQ3U1DWgo+MRY8eGCXfknlgMZnPm4Gp8HxvH2LFjQh25c+cOmJiYoBOenl8x9v9jYGCAXY1wJDMzAzw8PMDZ2RkOHToMzc23mWY4rl79A\/z8\/MDJyQl27NgBZWVlTPNyFBcVwTQdndfa4OfPZ4O1lRUYGxvDzp1+IJE8ZRoeEkkX2NrawpGQEMYwR\/r7+8HBYRXeRFVVFQwN+dSopqYOFy\/moaGAgwcOoI6O2bNnD14HBn7LLEbjh5MnB+0Sk84xVjbq6mrRbsGC9yAgIACvV65cxbQ8gvbvQ76qupoxzJGQI8Go2OziCl0k91PEx8UhN4U48\/Qp\/0Yu5OYiN3fuu3Djxk3kqqurYPLbbyFfWjp6ZVJTUlBnRv5TRyr8q+Dl6Yn2dfUilH19vFFuaGxCWSKR4Mt2dHJGWQDX1toKOtpaoG9gCL29fYzm8fnGjWBnZwf3HzxAeYmtDU567VoFygIiwsPA0tIS8i9dZgwPsfguaKirA0eqekzMCagnjpSXlw8bLS0tzJrHxx\/Z4T3u3buPckREGMrJKako7\/b3R3lk2HOZpOehin37g5DofvYMnjx5MmwjUXR0tGNbMZ8sOUVfXy\/adXd3oywLe3bvxrn\/a+wPOsiseaxZ7YD8w4ftKB8MCkK5sqoa2tsf4vWuXXtQNxTc4cOHUBkdfQJ8fX1w2ahsaGgEkVHRzIzf4JR3cv4CY16HbVwNDQ3w9vYZDMmhKCgogPj4eBxxJFRjY2NHjeqaGmbN41xSIs4bFR0D\/5AsN1NPD7R1pqHOw90NlJVVyAvsRHkoONqJcpwCifPJoEKcoJs2ODgYtFiPFBAQiIYZ6Wkoq5MiRn83bdpMlj0CPrCwQNnKyhpevHiBtmMBTTxurq44J200p+vqQlFRMbSSEKRcYOC+QbvHjx\/jNQXnvW0bGkyZogYi0XVG8\/Gto61NJlMkS9oBl\/Lz0Y6OuPiTzIrHsmWfIJ+QcJoxY0dtbS2mdSH1rli+DJ+RviyanmlmVVJSgnnzzEnCqQFuK64IB1+SNzwSQgZJTU2DstLf8HrWLAOmlSI7Kwt169atZ8z4orz8Ks5\/NjEJHj3qIHtVEebPX0DqXiaYmhiDru4M4MLDjqORt48v+5sUQr4OD48cXFpjY1OmleL3K1dQZ2OzhDGk862oAHfSGLq4uLxyJCQksH\/JBs2W08nDUkRHReG9Ll0uQJkWcSpzV8jy0YsPLRehYihW2C9HXQ45S9AsRkON7qOWllZmwSMyIhztvLZuYwzfjuTk5ODIJfWnsLCQ1JlSKCkpgby8vEEdHZWVLz+T5BNbOvepU7yzoUdDUL7Z0IByTU01yhyNObulS1GIiIxEJYUwwQy9mfCMpGSKneS4Srn16z+D3j6+5tA6ZGhggHx5+Z\/IyUJnZyfWkebmZsa8HmjozNI3IDWuF+Ww49\/hvYqLS1AWygdWdnqm1prKZykb0sM4OPC5XElZGS4ShwTQurF40SLUGRkZ4dFVSNffsOw2ErQuuZLwwZuxYWxsAllZ2czi5Ug8exbtcy9IT5eNZCXoHqERRPeIibBHmB5ukze1l5zazM3NwdTUFFxICqyqqmJaKegKRpE4tba2xk7W3t4e0tLSmXY4Bgb6Ye2a1fgwa9eug2ISVr+cOQOqKiqYDWW1NAJ6yH0sFi4kncVHjJEiIz0dDEgUYNYiz4tZi+nkgjKyJ\/gVGJ4ghKInK1MK6COh29bWhr+yMKqOsF+54LpIBMeOhZI+KYUxPESienRkDVml8YJcHZGF58+fg7OjIzpyJOQoY8eOCXNEfPcuOBIH9PX10QlvHx+mGR9MmCPns7NBj6Ry4dBGe7NC0kONFybMEaEW0U16IiYGndHUfOfN\/Yoi4NMV9uhM0iuOvq8LuTqSkpKMdebX5GTGSOHluQUdCX0TvjSe+fk0Pqy1jS1jeIjFYuzbqO6N+PZLuwBrq8X4wI6OTljZ09PSBnuzreQsNF6Q+x6hbYq\/vx8eiRUVFdEBM7O54\/qVEQDgX8+aImqoij18AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle; width: 40px; height: 26px;\" \/><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> more than their cost price.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>1\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>2\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>3\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>4\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu12":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>15<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">For &minus; 1 &lt; <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">r <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&lt; 1, if <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">F<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">r<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">) = 8 + 8<\/span><em style=\"font-family: Arial;\">r<\/em><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + 8<\/span><em style=\"font-family: Arial;\">r<\/em><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + &hellip;&hellip;., find the value of <\/span><img height=\"36\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAFMAAAAkCAYAAAD1lQZ5AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAuzSURBVGhDvZoJWFXVFscVREQzcx5QJp\/6NLWnmTiA2vccU6wcAZVBQyHBnlJaL0QBsxTLqRwSMYenoGiAKTLoS0EkNUegMkiRQQFfioCJmuvtte66cO8959wBr\/2+b3+w\/nffffZZ9+xhrX0agBm5f78Cdu3cCQ8fPmRFyrlz5yA1NY0t81NWVgp79uyBJ0+esGI6NwsKIDYmli3jMasz\/d55B7KysthSxn\/ePDiVns6WefH29obs7Gy26s+nK1fC1q1fs2UcBp35oLoaSktL4datW5Lyv99\/51oAc\/38YOGiYLb0k5+fD3Z2dpCXl8+Kfu7evQu3b9+W7UO16J+aKZMnwycrP2Xr2aipeQi9evWC+IREVgxj0Jles2ZB06ZNwcbGRlI+\/WwV1ckRT0Lz5s2h\/M4dso3Bx9sL3NwmsqVMdVUV9OjeHZo0aSK5PvYrM\/MM1Us\/dQpatWqld4oxlahtX4OjoxP8+eefrOhHrzOxkU4dO0IXO3ua63TL7\/xkzvT0hFf+0Y\/+N5akpKNgadkIiotLWJEnO\/sqNGjQADw8PGX78OjRI6o3auQ\/YeTIUfS\/uSgpLqZrJ6eksqIfvc4svHmTGvP2mc2KlBrxJLzwQjPwD3iXFRU1NTXCUcX0gyQlJUFqWprWonCT29769TZW5Nm39z9UL+7gIVak3Lt3T\/wwlrBseRgrxlNSUkJ9\/Sk3FxITE2nqUPNU9L1N69ZiHvZhRT96nZmSnEw3sm9fDCtScnNyqM5XmzazomLd2i\/gxRdbwKBBg6Br167gJAp2Wg06wEYM3enT3VmRJ3jRQmq\/rLycFSmZGRlUJzZ2PyvGUSrm4VYtW8KAAa9B\/3794IVmzSA+PoE\/VfFq\/37gIIb6YyN2B3qdGREeRp2cNGkyBAcHa5WoqO1U58Tx41TnQNxBstV4eriTHhYWTkMxLy+PP6nD0dEBBg8ZypY8ri5DqZ2goAWSPpw8eZLqxMUdoDppx0+QbSzf\/\/cEfa9P31egXPxYhYWFYntXyZ+q8HCfDlZW1mIurnsQlNDrzLFjxkCjRlbg6uoKzs7OWmXFik+oztYtm6lDmk8FDm0He3vxRP6NFXm6d+sGnTvbwePHj1nRpqLiHrR86SXoKOZtfMJ1+5CckkL1VkREUB9SjJzb1KxetYq+l5FxmhUpM2d4goWFBVy\/fp0VZRSdiTfYtk0b6NnrZVbk2bJpk8SZBQU3SAtdpn8OQ2fadu5Su4jo8uP589TOB4uXsCKPrjNxRQ8NDYWFCxfKlm1RUVRv7JjR0LZtO70b\/Dpn\/saKMorOzPv1V+qgl4HJ97hYWLBenMYwP\/LdYdK+52GohJOTIwwePIQtKTuit1M7+uZsJO6A9jDHH2fv3r0QHR0tWzACw8WlbZvW8Nbbk+g7Sszw9IBGVo2fbZjHf3uIOrjxy69YkUe9AH3+xVpWAJYvC4WGDRuKlfE2K1Jws92iRQuYMnUaK1IC\/OdR29nZOazIk3n6NNXbuXMXK4YpuKEaPatWR7Iij8vQoWBn7yBG6jMsQEGB8+li53\/8kRV5cIjgvObjW7d9em3Aq\/BSy1ZsyXPzZgG1r94aRW+PEqvqAMg4nUk2zrv2XbqAVWNrrV2AHBilWVlZwZIPP2LFMPtjY+n6aWnHWZHy9OlTsTVqZXB0qlF0ZuTq1TBLRD+VlVWsKDNnti\/0erm3yhAdCPD3F7\/4apWtQPKxJNobFhUVkx2zby+MGzcOzp47TzbuX71FlBQeHkG2IdwmTIBhw0ewZZhvDx0SgYAH3NETtd0Se1B0+LFjqoXOEIrONIWcnGwR7tmIDXDdhtcQvt7eMGGCG1vPTkb6KRE8NIdKEX6ai6ht28DBwdHoDJRZnIlgxigwMIgt\/WCU4eToCNeuXWPFPEyeNKleUZASuJE\/KJ5gYzGbM3Femzp1qti8x7EiD8bzmCYzpZPGcr+iAtzc3CA52bhhqQTeS2joUlhpYgbKbM5Ug\/GtPjASOnv2LFvPhyPfHeH\/6kdlZSUkJR1jy3gaHD58GGbPng0+Pj4mlfmBgfSEeXl51Wrv0FAPrLU9PT0hICAAfH19azU\/Pz9RZ36tbe6C7c+fPx\/8xSI4Z84cmDlzpmw9fQX9ERQUpNVvXIzRxnbRxv91Q+QGV69ehaNHj5pUTpw4AUuWLBZxsyskJCTI1sHy0YcfgouLC20\/5D5\/XiVFhJmbNn0FvXv3hl27d8vWMbVgYNBPzKHr128Q95NGGsbzmtRrmBcVFcKokaNE7FzBijKLFi2EzziJ\/Fcyfvx4uHjhIlvmAQOU10e8DtUPHrCijZYzE+LjYc2aNRAWFiYpWVk\/cC2AISIE3LxlK1v6wfmnY4cOtZvxZyE\/Pw\/WrVsHESIW1+3f5i1buBbAgqBAMbxnsWVeMCXo5vYmWyoOxh0AW1vbOmfiXqpdmza0Se3Tp4+kpPCJ4rGkJLARe8rqavlfR445Yg5ydR3OVv1ZERFO\/bO3t5f0b948f6pTUlIM1o0bQ9YPz2eRu3HjOlhaWGiFuGcyM2m9qHWmOtOjGRbKMXrUSHB2HsyWcajj\/BsFBazUj7ffehMsLCwlOUdNVn6ygs6H\/vjjD1bMj22nTmIBlu6pa52ZJCZUvGF9xwgPHlSDtYiB\/ebOY0UFZpgiIyMhNTUVpkyZQslkzTD08qVL1PY3ComIW7dKDG6XnohYvbNtJ+jRoycr8gwdMhj+3rMXW6aDCRic6vBe\/vXeezB69Gi4dOkyf6pixPBh4OjUla06ap2pHkJnxNyISQbNos43XvvlF6qzYeOXZKvBpwF12062sHjxYnB3d9fKUd4WEY9Fw4Ywl4eiLrt37YSBA53Zkqe4qIiuMcvLmxIQmv3D3Cv9Fdd8sXlzvZkoQ2SdyaTr4NO9YMECiqqu6pzDvxvgT1mx0tIyVlTUOnOCWP2wkdatW0O7du20yvKwcKqDx6lYZ9PmuskecZ82jfRT6RmsaIO\/tlUjS5g6bTor2uyPjYERYpXUx+HEBLqGtbW1pH99+vQVo+YB7S4aWVqC54yZ\/C3TweNdvE54xApWpIQuDaE6efnaCeNaZ+IpXLdu3SEmJoYSq5rl559\/pjo7oqOpEc2VHJ+KDu3bQ\/\/+A1iRgit6s6Y2dNaiBm8eD9WwYPrNRexZ1TYW3aOMZSK8w2tjNkq3f0eOHKU6Vy5fpjqaKTPN60iKcD4+0ZqoM+v4uRKhS1V90T0mIWdWiC\/ih76z55CoRKrYDOs68\/pvv5EWGbmGFSlVVZXQWMy1E998ixWgeQnnIyx9+\/alFwjUttw8NW7sWFp80DlK4Dm3paUFzNDYFq1ft1arXc3yxhvj6W0VNTh92HXpDMMNjJKlIR\/TPefm\/sSKCnKm0vDVJTdXlVXXzL4nJsSTdvLkKVak4AtdlhYNxU6h7sfCc5qqqioqO7\/ZIbZOw2ptLJppr0c1NXTE0K1bD7phJbBeEzENaE4nmteRK5rtlQnH4r2ELA1lRZ6PRPSH9TTP2BFy5hefr6EPfzCwot6\/f5+esLkaq3nIx\/+m75aWaU\/Gmvwipgmss2Gj\/BGIoTkTN+v4fW8fX1bkQccMfG2AwUNAJdRHvwmJh1mRx238G9ChYydJnpOcOUF8iI0Yk1Uf5uoCQ4a4sAXgPHAgtGvfQe8Tk5J8jNrPzsllRZs9u3eJvesgtqSgs\/H72\/isXh+4ODRt2syoAzBd1O8JGDrW7erkCB6eM9iqg5yJe7wzZ1QvQBlin5jwVZ1VvSCVnp4OFy9eov+V+OD9YL1PC75ZceHCBbak4PuSmFy5e1d5UVCDe17ctly+fIUV48kRsTdeR3dR0qS8vIwiILlpjZxpCriXc3Rw0DraNQTWj91\/gK3nz8SJbkZn\/U0FX\/vp3\/9VtrQx2ZlImogOcFgakzXauGE9HVz9lRQVFlK6zBwvvWpyp7ycTlAvXJTPRtXLmQg6dLWBM+erV65ASEgIW38t+Abf+8HviyGrPJebSkR4uKIjAQD+D1Tz2goVqxQ7AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"84\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>2\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>4\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>8\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>16\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu13":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>15<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">If the product of three consecutive natural numbers is 16 times their sum, which of the following gives the sum of the squares of the three numbers?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>110\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>171\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>149\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>194\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu14":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>15<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">If <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">= |<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ 1|&nbsp;<\/span>&minus;<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;|<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&minus; 2|, then which of the following is true of <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t\u2212<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9999999\">3 \u2264 <i>y <\/i>\u2264 0 <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT2":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t\u2212<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9999999\">3 \u2264 <i>y <\/i>\u2264 3 <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT3":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9999999\"><i>y <\/i>\u2264\u00a0<\/font><\/span>\u2212<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9999999\">3 <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9999999'><i>y <\/i>\u2265 3\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu15":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>15<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Usually, Mahesh takes 150 minutes to drive from his house to his in-laws&rsquo; house. Last Sunday, after covering 20% of the distance to his in laws&rsquo; house, Mahesh&rsquo;s car developed an engine problem, which reduced his speed (when compared to his usual speed) by 15 km\/hr for the remaining part of the journey. If it took Mahesh a total of 190 minutes to cover the entire distance, find the distance (in km) between his house and his in-laws&rsquo; house.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>120\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>150\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>240\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>270\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu16":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>16 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>17<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">How many positive integers less than or equal to 2020 will not have any zero in them when represented in the number system to the base 5?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"852","CORRECT_ANSWER":"852","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu17":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>16 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>17<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">A triangle is constructed in the <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">-<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">plane, with the vertices of its base lying on the line <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">= 36, and the third vertex being the origin, such that all the vertices have integer co-ordinates. How many such triangles can be constructed, if no portion of the triangle lies outside the first quadrant and the magnitude of its area is a positive integer?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"666","CORRECT_ANSWER":"666","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu18":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>18 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>22<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Cities A, B and C are interconnected in such a way that one can go directly from A to C or go from A to C via B. One can go from A to B in <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">ways, from B to C in (<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ 2) ways and directly from A to C in 2<em>n<\/em> ways. If the total number of ways in which one can go from A to C is 60, find the value of <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>7\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>8\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>5\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>6\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu19":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>18 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>22<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">A tank has four emptying taps, all of equal efficiencies, but each fixed at <\/span><img height=\"30\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAkAAAAdCAYAAAB41kadAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAGkSURBVDhPzZPNSwJRFMVnZ2AqKCgYZGEgFfTxT2RQMFKtNDAwt7mvFoatCqp1Hwu1QJ0pBBGxhZuir4221J3gwhl0UQsrNU\/jLUZTaVXQgQPz7vnd9x6XNwx66OKch2fNg\/r7O627oLvbG+h0WgwOmr4qbZAoiHCvusAwDJRKJUxDw6jWapTJEMdFoNVqEQpHsOJ0Qq3WdEPPz0+oVF7oe9nhgKpf3Q21y2G3Q6X6X5CNZWkUP0K7OztYXFxCrV6ndU+oU78I5fN5JBIJxOPxnm5mDMdxcLvdcLlcPd3M\/uDiuVwW0WgUPM\/LTiYvKZOhBZuNptxus3mEMhkaMBoxY52FIAjSKxVQKBRQLBYpI6harVLn3v4B3l5f8SK5XQTlslmCLBYLNBoNFAoF5ubnIYpiCwqHQgSxrA2pVAoBvx99fQpMTE62oHK5jFgshkajQcWmjo8OqfHu\/qF18U5dX18RdHR88glt+3yYmp7+ttNpIEBQOvP4CZ0Fg1RY39ikozOZNHTSPzg6Nk4N8nFbXi\/0ej1MpiEYDAZYpZmVSmUpAT4ANDRVaK4MUggAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"9\" \/><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> th, <\/span><img height=\"30\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAkAAAAdCAYAAAB41kadAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAH7SURBVDhPrZO\/TxpxGMYv2IEJFk9Coo0spC5EE3GuJup\/4NGkrMURNk0QTVBM\/NXBBo2emqpFxS4qk00Ig1UUbNXEBgUmJjkjXeoAhMe79847RdJ06JM8udz7fL73fn\/cl4GicrmMxYUFuFwuMs\/zqCiZCjk4Dnq9Hk6nU\/R76HQ6Ee6njKBv+\/tgGAZLyytUlDQeCFDt8OhIhq6vruD3+\/Hn\/p4ASSfHcYI2Nre0dtXqd30gKJ\/P14Y+zc4SMDoWoPcX0NTkBAEDg4NK5QlULBbF1cgteH5JqcpSIY7rg8FgxOXlL6WiiaC93R36QmtrG7xeLzweD9xuNzmRSMjQyPAwbDYbrFYrzGbzM29vf5WhSuXxAGpLndPf9G+QIAhIJpM0wVqWMiYUCsHhcIhbwNW0lP3HOSlP5HI5xGIxRKNR1fH4MWUq9E7sL+36Uzc3WyhToddNjXjb2YV0Oo1MJo1UKoVsNksZQaVSkUZOz3ykYrUIymYyBEnn19DAwmA00tILhd8atLW5QVBPby8ikQjmgkG8qquD3d6hQfmbG4TDYZTEu\/eo+bkgDUwkT7WJV+v7wQFBi+JfStB4YAzt7Xb1xkr6sr5O0I+fZzK0tvqZCkNDPtwVCrg4PwdbX483LS00QG034vOBZVlYLBaYTCZ0d\/dAEG7FBHgAxBo1LrYB0FkAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"9\" \/><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> th, <\/span><img height=\"30\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAkAAAAdCAYAAAB41kadAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAInSURBVDhPrZNNbxJRFIYn1BUkUrCUxYApm6bd4KbThXWhprR\/QAR\/AGFLUne1xI22G3XXNrFN\/agorDE2xRAWkNSAH8VgicCCEEjKiAgb5CO+3jnDjI7BxIVvcjJzz\/vc3HNmzuUwVKvVwsbGOvx+PwKBAE5O8kMHUCHX4iLMZjN8Ph\/mBQE2ux25XI48gra3NsFxHJLJFCV7vS7MpnFcXLhEa4LK5TIOD2OUUGS38ZienqF39ThJ3zsdpFIp3FxZgdFoxKuDA8proI\/ZLBwOB3Q6HXibjdX0ifIaqNftosuiVqvigtOJcZMJ7XZbhgaDAer1OoGKXkaj1Ew681aGbq2usvbPocNqUrS9KXf8uVCUodexGCXc7uvIZDKIhMO0FoR52qDW9GhvDzzPQ6\/Xw2Aw4JrbjWq1Rp6m8MGgz4wqGo3GMCNLA\/1N\/waJokjFptPpkSF5XCgUgtfrhcfjGRmS9x9rGj5RqVSQSCQQj8fVODp6Q54K3WDnS1\/595iacpCnQuftNly+chWFQgHFYgH5fB6lUok8gvr9Hu28d\/8BJf8UQaUi+9MMcrIZmpy04CybSqn1ZvPbLyj84jlBS8vLiLI52mJjcmZsTDsF9dNTRCIR9NnwKVJukDp0o5RKJgl6uLMrQ+t372BuTsAPsmU9298n6N37DzL09MljSqytBfG12UT2+BiWiQnMzM7SBvW428EgLBYLXSmr1QqXawmi+IU5wE9pgjafxs42xQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"9\" \/><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> th and <\/span><img height=\"30\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAoAAAAeCAYAAAAVdY8wAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIWSURBVDhPtZNPbxJRFMXHBBsSBqfajhZr6q7VaFsJNY1T2kWnEgQTdKkuGpcNy\/oZbDHWtK7qygIb1EBCUr9ADUkhdWM3sGjRlNTAhhAQaPlznLk8B4KDrnqSm8y59\/dm7ntzHwcdFYtFeL1erK29YRlAF\/QuLYHjOLjdD1lGB9xYXyfIaDRifn6BZbvAxO4uQSsvV3BjdBSSZGeVDrBQKEAcHMADl5v81aEhfdDtcmFk5Drq9Tr5K5dF2O1z9KyKQP\/We\/rklj+AdPoQyWQSgwOXYLXakEqlUKvVWuDc7CyBvSL9\/UcLjMfjiEajiEQiFOFwGP3CBYyN3ST\/q1xu99iti\/0Cpqcl5nTOUVWz2cSdyQl4PI9ZpgeoqlKpoFo9Ye4fYLfOAAwGg3Apf8XpdPYMtc5ls1nlb6T\/G2e4mf39b5BlGTabTRkGqxav2XXQwLcbrcm+J0lwOBxabG6+o7oGPnv6BOf7+pj7Wxo4fvsWxicm8XVvD6FQCLFYjFVaIrB2egqzmYfBYADP8xAEgdqQ5QXk8\/k2+PP4GCaTCTMzdhwcHCrDUEUg4CfY43nUBlXlcjmUlQHt1H3lFFRYvXgENhoNlEolKnbq+eIigUdHmRb4eXubevvw8RMBf6QOL8+baZAJzGQyOKesHB6+hngiQT2\/WF6mt\/l8r2iR1uOXnR3cnZpSdm+GxWKBKIpYXfWxKvAbVmi2231OF9QAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"10\" \/><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> th of the height of the tank respectively. Two filling taps, each of which individually can fill the tank in 200 minutes, are also connected to the tank. If the ratio of the efficiency of each emptying tap and the efficiency of each filling tap is 1 : 3, and all the six taps are opened simultaneously, then in how much time will the empty tank be filled?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>166 minutes\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>174 minutes\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>182 minutes\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>154 minutes\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu20":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>18 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>22<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Find the value of <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">k <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">such that the pair of equations 6<em>x<\/em> + 9<em>y<\/em> = 24 and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">kx <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ 6<em>y<\/em> = 16 has an infinite number of solutions.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>4\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>6\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>9\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Cannot be uniquely determined\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu21":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>18 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>22<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<font style=\"font-family: Arial;\">In a textile shop, the number of shirts having a design is thrice the number of shirts not having a design. The shop also has sarees of exactly three colours&nbsp;<\/font>&minus;<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;Brown, Black and Yellow. The number of brown sarees is half the number of black sarees and one-fifth of the number of yellow sarees. Find the number of shirts not having a design, given that the total number of shirts and sarees in the shop is 72 and the number of sarees that are handspun is four times that of those that are not handspun.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>9\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>8\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>7\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>6\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu22":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>18 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>22<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">The price of a commodity increased by 30%. Find the percentage reduction in the consumption of the commodity by a family, if the expenditure on the commodity by the family decreased by 9%.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>20%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>23.75%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>26.25%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>30%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu23":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>23<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Nagesh took six AIMCATs and the total score that he obtained in each AIMCAT was a distinct number between 121 to 130, both inclusive. If the average of his AIMCAT scores at the end of every AIMCAT was an integer, and he scored 127 in the sixth test, how much did he score in the fifth test?\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"123","CORRECT_ANSWER":"123","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu24":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>24<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>In how many ways can 195 be expressed as the sum of two or more consecutive positive integers?\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>3\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>4\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>5\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>7\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu25":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>25<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Aniket has three pen stands and 13 distinct pens, exactly three of which write with red ink. One stand can hold six pens, one can hold four pens and the third can hold three pens. In how many ways can Aniket put all the 13 pens in the three pen stands such that all the three red ink pens are in the same pen stand. (Ignore arrangements of the pens within a pen stand)\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"5250","CORRECT_ANSWER":"5250","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu26":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>26 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>30<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">If <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">are positive integers such that <em>a<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + 64<em>a<\/em> + 1188 = <em>b<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">, which of the following gives the value of (<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&minus; <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">)?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>2\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>34\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>42\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>50\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu27":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>26 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>30<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">How many distinct values of <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">are possible such that (log<\/span><em><sub style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/sub><\/em><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"><em>x<\/em>)<\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">1<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">0<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">1<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> = log<\/span><em><sub style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/sub><\/em><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(<em>x<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">1<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">0<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">1<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">), if <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">is a positive real number and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">is an integer between 1000 and 2000 (excluding both)?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>999\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>1000\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>1999\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>2997\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu28":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>26 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>30<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<font style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Amar was walking towards a building at a constant speed. In ten minutes, he observed that the angle of elevation of the top of the building changed from 45<\/font>&deg;<font style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;to 60<\/font>&deg;<font style=\"font-family: Arial;\">. How much more time will he take to reach the foot of the building?<\/font><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='115' Height= '26' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAHMAAAAaCAYAAACEuGN0AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAoeSURBVGhD5ZoLVI\/ZFsBrihhjPGcwd03kEZUeihnPO6u7ljszCcujuAapFFMNUsljDSqXZcijMlelyOglKkZFGe9erJFiIY+pyONaeick9t17f+erf+kvhSX\/+1vrrM7e53zne+xz9tn7\/FODFnL+\/J9w4sQJIbVOjh8\/hs+ZJSTVp0XGrKmpASsrK3hYVCQ0rZM7hYUwefJkIak+LTLmPEdH8PXdJKTWjecSD3BydhGSatNsY+bn5YGu7kAor6gQmtbNg\/\/eh169ekF+foHQqC7NNqaHuxtYjLMU0quhPXXDhg2vLPv37xe93x1jRo+GZctXCEl1abYxe2trw8aNvkJSTiHuV7q6urBixYpXlqCgIHHFu8PbazX07z9ASKpLs4x54\/p1+EhdHaPEpqPY8PBwmDVrlpDeL8lHDoOamjpOsDtCo5o0y5i7w3bhR1GDvPx8oVGOk5MT+Pn5Cen9ci03l5973\/5YoVFNmmVM10UL+aOUlZULjXLGjh0LWVmtI8crLyvj5\/ZcukxoVBM25nPMG69cuQKXL1+uV0pKSriTjOU4C+j+2efw+MkToWmchw8fwmgMOqqqqoQG4NKlSxAWFgb79u2H0tJSoX03xMfHQ27uNSGhMcvLoV07LbAcP0FoWs7hpCSIjIyEp9XVQvN2KC1582\/Cxjxx\/BjP3IbF3z+AO8kMGjgQDA2NhKScQ4cO1UvWV678mcfr0KEDaGpqQo8ePSE5JUW0vl3C9\/zG99qyZavQSBjo68HAQXpCajn6eoN4\/OIGE72lXMc4xNzcHAICtglNy2Fjrlv7b37A8IgIOHjwYG3Jb7A30ovoGwwWknI8PT1hzZo1XI+OiuKxHRwcobLyEdy+fQv66ujAZ7jCHz16xH3eBs+ePYNf1q\/ne1EJDt4hWiQM9PVh8GtMxKaorKzEbaYMnj9\/LjRvxq6dofy8e8IjhKblsDEnThgPOn37skIZ5eVl0OHj9mAyxFRolGNhYQGnTp3ienxcLB\/9kauT8XBz4xfIzs4RGuVUVT2CW7duCalxKisrQHdAfx6TPAL9DQysn\/KYGBnB5+gRHj9+LDQAeXl5EBcXx5N2I+a8rq6uGIVLH5WCpqVLl8KSJZ6Qnp7OOiI9PQ2Sk5O5XlBQUHv9tm0BsHDhQggJDWWDE9VPn3L7n+fPs0xUo3smXU7ORaioqACHuXP5eefOdYCzZ8+KXtK58uLFi7kcO3ZcaCVojD3ogRYsWADu7h5wXJyRq9GMNjI0BFNTM5g1cyaMGDEC5s2fD9eu1e05RHFxEaYlamBqNlRoGqeoqAhGjhypdNXRrDYxNoIvv9R+rZX5xx9HwayJexYXF4O9vT1k5+SgEa7yx9m+PVC0Sgw1M2X9Q+wrE+Dvz7pP0P3roLcYMGAAy+bm\/4Bu3brhNzGF9u3bgzqmYydOSpNzoK7UhwgOCuQ6bR998HoDAwOWhw8fge9WhcYqZ9l62nTuT5Tg\/UlnZ+\/Ap2l0rTwGGYaYYzObdfroTahQfbbNHG6rQXv9E4NL0pmZmUGfPr25vnz5ClC7ioGPxkfqrJgwcSKfu2pptYVu3bvz7JGh2dalcycwNhkiNBI0GRRJTEyESZMmCamOClyZ48aNg44dP8F7qUN6RqZoeTUpKclgZGQspKY5m5nB79LQmDSBGq7M4KAg7kvGe\/HiBeuMjQxZFxgoXZ8rJoeD4zyWaVJotGnLdTlV++Ybc\/7xgXB2+pF19O1eoCum+hxbO24jSnGvrdXhPYMCt7O8HT0Jue6YvdEsR2CQJRMVGcG6hMQkuHnjOtcDtv0qWgGmT7OGb7\/7DtQKCvI5uVfcY+QXGDv2W6GRMBxsgDPFgOvkNn18fKB3796wdWtdsEGuydvbW0h1UH9fX19Yt24t9OrZE1fvKLh3755oVU5aWioMHTpMSE2jzJi8Zw42FJKEbMxdYbuFBtDt2bPuCbpIogq9B8k2c2xZJmNqCmOG7ZKMGREZxTKx57fdrIuNi0djoevDulJjIqEhO1gOCd3JssX3aBSUY2L28VEnlZiYGNZNnWrNmYKGhgb07dcP1mOMkJ2dXTsRJX\/RCGboYtTVNaAU3aLMYAN90BPGpH1jxowZoK2tjautY226YWlpCSdPnuS6MlKSj\/DDyW6lITRbp0yZwmXMmDHQuXPnWplKytGjoufLKDem3kvBm2zM4B0hQgNgb2fLutJS6b3lj29nP5dlRWPKwUtGZp2X2REsjSkbh+q2dvZcJxoaU+6\/QzyDibExplHtoGvXrtCpUycuXbp04W1gvEitfsfglI5K6Toq\/dCwe8nglF8GBATAgwcPuKOMIfr\/jp92qpcrWltNhbZaWvWCmQMHDvCAa9euZXnUqFG8h8mcO3eOV2SNQvRXXf2Ur5k2\/V9CU5+bN27AmTNnuGzduoV\/pZFlKvfv3xc9X6YxY9Lz0tZhZT1NaCRkYwYpeCU72zmsKxF53+sYM1MhcJGNI692qttjcCPzGL8n6WRjyvuubMzhX38Fn6IBaTt4gvk8FUJ24zU1z2pjjQsXsjB99Me9Xgr+1EKCg7my2qvONWZfuMA62bXILFvqyXrFEyBa4np6etAd99iEhASYiPuuIvPnOfI1iUmHhQZdkcgFf9mwUWiUc+bM6SYDIEUaNaY4AVJ8R+JtGbOxlblzVxjL7XDyK+bmh34\/yO0OjvNZlvdM2VX7eHuxTG5WJivrPMYNRhAVFQ2nMUvQwjFpJcrsDA3ha9Ro5X1PmycKs2bPBg93d2iDiX2vL\/4GhXfqH0wnJSZwv9wGkW5sbCzr6XdD8uOKFBbehn6Y9mhqtgFnZxeYj5Ey9TU2NsEV0\/Rvool4zz59dITUNGmpp3l8xUMD+Ww2ISFRaCT8\/fxY76dwOGI1dQrrioulQwE5+pRXdb++OiwT2\/\/zK9dPp6ayTAT41x\/T6Ufpfa2srfm8mrYMkmWvlIqTleQRmAFE790LRbgnUnZBOhsbG3BxdmZ7tMEJlJl5lgPJnj16cDtlHWSvjzFlHD16jLRnkkHXYDAzZMgQnEWG4Ozigsn9bb6ZIvfu3uUwPS7+gNBIyKuTbpCq8GIy9O8bLjgmjW2C0TAFTvLMbwpKkTZtev3\/ariFuZ8b5rFpaXW54ZHDSRw03MHnVyQD80fqm56RITR0yBHJuqoqKeolt0hydPReljdv3gQeHku4fg7dK7VRvimTkVF\/zCfoLlevWoWT1xi+Hj6cV9yWzZvRO4VzO+WMrosWwbBhw8BWuF6KP3x8vGvtQTmo4vHkX3\/dxBzzJ26j4uLyE+\/xSgMgZQzF3MbNzV1IdaSkpHAS+1REga2JVSt\/blZE\/KHSbGNuwVVCLvJD4u8YEW\/8QP5n6U1otjEpIKDc8srVXKFp3dy9e4dPUeQ9UJVptjEJby8v+OGHmUJq3bgtdoXVq72EpNq0yJiEPSbCr3NQ\/j65eDGHI8L\/DwD+ByNohT4d1IklAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>5 minutes\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='84' Height= '17' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAFQAAAARCAYAAABD\/oseAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAcFSURBVFhH7Vh9VM53FH8qJBNzIpXirDcqtiVqm5JSzDkxW6eHSrYMrTnyR1KE1ESehMwi0avCKc1bo7ybUV56YWS9aaVOkd5VhLvvvc\/31\/O0lB3aOTvmc87vPPfe7\/f+ft\/v53fv\/d7fI4JeQEFBAXh4eLzyKiws5B5vL3qFUB8fHwgICIDMzMwerxcvXnCPtxdvTOjz58\/B2toaysrKuOX\/jTcm9M6dO2Bra0vEvkMvEBofHw\/u7u5cewcitL6uDnbt2gXbt2\/vdOXn59OknrBs2TIIDw\/nGsDVq1dhyZIl4OjoCKGhodDQ2MhHeg+7IyPB2dkZSktLueXNUVlRAbm5uVx7fRChh1KSQSQSdbliY+NoUk+wt7eHnJwcko8c\/pn81NXVwcHBgWRDw9FQVVVN472FlX6+oKenR+WmN5DHiNTQ0AA\/v1Xc8vogQpd7e4OCohJUVlbC48ePoZFFVW1tLTx58oQmdYfy8nI6kNrb26GttRWUlfuBptYIaGUy4vy5c0Sqv\/9q0v+ryEhPp3WGh+\/gltcHEWozxRomTLQgQ1NTE\/3+Exw8eJBSD4GEop6ZmUU6ovbRI1qos4srt3RFBUs17FGjo6PB1cWFIm\/69M\/h2rXrcPrUKbCwMAcDAwMqI\/iiEQkJ8eDp6QkPa2qgnHUX6B8XF8fWMpf87VjWHDt2nOYifFesgNDNm7kG1L55syCKiNgJjQ0NYDlpEq3TxGQsmxdGc7AMrl7tD2PGjKZ7LvXygvv3K2gMkc+yY+5c6fMMDQ3B19cPGti9RE1NjeSkra1Nl7KyMowcOQoS9iVy1+7hxR6ydetWrsnQ0tICxcXF4LF4MaipqbG6eo2PdAWmG24GLzs7OwgKCgIFBQXo27cfqKqqsoX6wqJFC2n8O8\/vycd5jpj0AvahcP36tQ5\/B4eZEBgYCIMGqZKem5tH81XYnj786GOSES9YR6LInjHJcjIRamUpIzQsbAtl2AQzM7J5ey+HtWvWwAAVFeKllhHd2toCI7S0QFdXD4KDg4kHnDvFxhZEuaz+oaKhqUkndkZGBtja2JAt5VAqXwIr2qwcZGXJog+B9fPGjRtck2HjhmAYMmQI3ePLrxy59eX4\/dYtmmduLs0QxA+B68gWuTuKWwD0dD+A0WOMSF7MCS4uKWGkSddvZ2dPY4hf0o6TLS4+gfQRbG9Wk61JRiChw4YOBdupdqRfOC8tTdu2\/Uh65M6dpOfl3SQdUfPwIdk2hkig7M9SkiWhsqhPStwHGzeGgKixsQGSk5NZgZed6G1trTCIRYepqRn1lxEREeytD6KbZGdn0xysn1ZWVmxuG+nywDQsKiqCPVFRoMB8xOI53fapAqELFnzLLSyl4+P4s6SHHWLcWBMwZhGEeBmh8pv79eJFsq1ZG0B6d4RO5S\/h2NEjNB8JQcyaKT1QZ8+eTd0KXmKxNCsw0rG84XpQNzUdT1+Jt2\/fJt9u+1Cz8aaUds3NzXDgwAFISUmhG8yYMYPGU1NTqYa8CvPd3MivvPw+t3SGQOg8t\/ncAhC9dw\/ZLl++wi0AJsZGYDJ2HMmdCOUZti8xicYQ586eJdvKVf6kI6HWU2xIFqA+bFi3hFpPtgIVluJisVMHoU5OTlR3168PpjkYSFhjDQz0yRcvdxYUomNHj4INS3H58EZoDFcHIyNjePZMFlnYwKMj9n8SiYTqnYAH1dVUAsK2dK6pXkuXkk\/Zv0xobFw8jSEEQlfx7mI4I8\/c4hOSBbw\/eDA7vKaTLLR7ISydEfNcXUBJSanT3hHC53V1VRUdwALQvmghI5PdQ3TyxAkSZs36oiN9JZJNZIvYuYt0ASVsA2jHt4UpcJGlloD6+joq3CoD3oN79+6RLfPKFejbpw9MZB3Eq1LedZ4btwDs3RNFNnlCjY1Gd6S8sHh5QmPkemaBUKGvtPzsU1BkbWFhYRHpoSwYcHwm2zMi\/aSUg\/XrN0j19JOkOzmJqY1ERPy0g2whmyTsmdkkL1y0uOMPnyBe9ynlt4RtJmUwe2s6OjokY\/i+DEKU6uvrd+lTs7IyWWQPp3FdXV36xcb+7t0\/+IyuuHXzJs2bM1fafiGidkeS7dKl37gFQF9PF\/TZvRDu33xN40Wsk8hhNR3lvdExNIY4c\/o02byX+0j1M6fpZSsoKlIno8V6ZR0dbTqVEQ8eVINK\/\/7MR6FjHYGcoIEDB4ImKxko20+bBjU1j2hcWIOa2lAYNWokyQHrAmU1tJqlbGJiInvTsT3+b4m9FhKPfWB3SEtLg5iYGLhw4QK39Aw8wOrr67km7RPRJg\/sVytYp4HAflR+\/O9zEWjD9k0A9pW4v8SkJHj6tB2aWb9dxVJXQElJMezfvx8OHznCLQB1zAfPj1jGycs+S5En7H9xr9KgAfgLQ7KST9tEVGIAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='116' Height= '26' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAHQAAAAaCAYAAABmZHgNAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAqfSURBVGhD3ZoHWFVXEscRKyyuFFuya1SQFhsIWCJqFF0xlhhN+GyomKVYcFWsdFFEabpqsGAUewNBBStgY4OCCxEBG0UQCwiKvaGTmXnn0kl4RA3y+777cf5zzn3vvjvnnJm5FwWoIcnJyXDy5EmhaidFb97Azh07oaioSFjqPjV2qIWFBeTk3Baq9uLv5wf+\/iuFqvvUyKGzZ80C98WLhardvHz5Ejp36gwJCYnCUreR26F379wGHW0dyC8oEJbaz9IlHmBuPkSouo3cDl3s7gb9+n0t1F\/D7du3YfXq1eDj41PlsXLlSnjw4AGPT09PA5W\/qUB29i3WdRm5HaqrowPu7h5C\/TWMHj0axo4dC05OTlUezs7OcOfOHR7\/7t07+Oc\/PoeVq\/7Lui4jl0Nzbt2C+vXrw+HwCGH5+Dx58gR69uwJr169EpbqMcR8MAwYMFCouotcDg0J3g8KCgqQmnpFWD4+p06dgqFDhwpVfeY6zAEVlaZyT4RPDbkc6uzkyA7Nzc0Tlo+Pp6cnLFiwQKjqs2HdOr72GzfShKVuwg6lwvvKlSu48lLLHFJSIWFh8QOoqqrC06dPhQUgLu4CBAUFQXh4OJcIH5oxY8bAvn37hAJ4jSvu2LFjfA2\/xMYKa0W2bQ1ih4b\/yXDx9u1b3KmC4eDBQ8Ly\/nj06JFo1Rx26JnTp\/nHlj\/8\/P15kISRoSFoanXgNk2CKVZWPK5Zs2b8V09PHxITf+X+D8Hr16\/B1NQUbmEsJ+ivgUFX\/m41NTX+O3Lkd5XemLgL57l\/zZq1wlIzXr16CcpNmkCr1p8Jy58nOfky9O7dG7Zt3yEsNYcdutxrGf\/Y7Tt2wKFDh4qPjMxMHiRhbNQN2rfX5PbSJUv4HM9ly3hlJl26BE1VVMDI2IRn8Yfg4sWLYGZmxm36DoOuXfgaIqOi2NlbNm9m7eGxhMeUJh53Eupbv2GjsNScx48fc3L2vvD39eFrC484Iiw1hx367Yjh0K5dezZUxfNnz0BDXQ30dPVZB\/y0FiwtJ3Jb4psh5nxheffvC0tF6Gbk5OQIJR9UW9rb23P7xYvnYG39b\/DyWs5aQrGeAph07yFUCRQa6NqcXVyFRUZiYiIcPnwYa9V0cMFSx8HBASLEjY2N\/YWfirm5uUMqhiSCJlJ0dDScPXuWdUpKCoSFhUFmRgb4eHvD7NmzYdfu3fBGPD9+huEpNDQUx6WyJp4\/f862a9euY1grgPHjxvK12c\/8T5knWidOnIBZ+P0Oc+fCGfF9ErSItm\/bBjNnzoR58+bB6TNn2K7w5s0bMOjSBQwNu8FES0vo1asX2NjYYEy9ygMknuKMVFZqAvr6XwpLWchJLVu0wK3DlOu+qqCLGDBAtsrkhWrPvXv3ClWRiPDDfGO8lpd1MiE51HLiJGGR8eMUWdhQVlaGjh07QquWLVkPGjQImjZtiruSEWsKK2lp6ezQRg0agEbzFnz+PLzZ0vl6enrQQUuL9bDhIzgsZWZmsJ49x4HHE1k3b7LN0ckZkpIu8bmkVXCHWyx2F4sfvmdb586dQVdXl9vW1jbcR7vRgP5fs83I2Bjatm1b\/HkKV3HmNaivyIbheBG2trbQBGOEqpp6mdny8sUL+Pyz1qCjoyssMmhmUlxTrFcPz1GDrKxs0VM5WzF56dOnr1DVp3z8LE3w\/v1gJG58\/\/6VT5aqVuhMXPFkt7GxZf2goADUMPEjW2RkFNuOHT3CetXqNaxbaGhAe00tbru5unLfmDFjWRPfjfyWbXl59+HevbvcXuToJHox9mdns23uvPk8+b1XLGe9a\/ce1pt\/3sQ6rFTiFbRFFk6iok\/BldQUbm8M3CR6ZRPAfMg3oJCVdRO3TkvYuDFQdAHOxBtQX1ER+vbrLywyenQ3gXYihkrQxS3HFeHi4gKqOIuHDhsGz3B7ror9mKGamQ0SqiK0Ag4ePMirZfDgwcWrPSEhAQYOrPzBwGlM6nx9ffF3TOBZ7u5e8cVBfFwc34TyMdR++nS2x8dfFBaA7ibGZX4n3Q8a4+Prx7q0Q11dcFVg37mY\/7EmVnh5se1CXDxPEGpX5VDC38+X9YEDoaxNe38FDRo0xG05DEJCQtB+AHbv3sVjJkyYCHm5uVAPF5C2jg6swG0+KSmJzyOqrEO\/6tWTP+B+fr6wiB+KsbaqLXXDhvV8TsC69cIiYxkmTvS4jg4T3CJa4NYsaTou4M2WyMvLg8mTJ4O5uSwe0w8iVq1aBTNmzOD27zFyxAg+79q1a8IiQ8pyAwLWCYsMyaExpRxCv1NTOIxISUnmMX7iNVxphzotWsR9N29msSY83N3ZdvzESSh8WMht2g4lcrJvsU1yqK+PN+vgkAOstTtogRJuw+q449FWT4e6ujompO3xfn3PY0LRydodOvB5dGhhe9\/+YFCg+nPt2rWQi14vDZUoSkrKmM2V1JxWkydBw4YNuSyIjIyEdeUcl3Uzkz\/cydlFWGRQTRsTE8MHJR4UryVNR0Elb25e4BZPMUxfX5aEWVtbw2bMYiWoPzAwEBOHsi\/ZN66XTaryNalUh0ZFRQuLDMmh587FCAvgpDMqzuaJ6ji0dKiRHBqJ3\/UQa3lql97q83LvsU1yqI\/3CtbBwbLJ2\/FLfWiNZRHlN5T8SPW99KKe7NIuSEndmjVrimO3ws+bArnhipmcREqy7AeMHTdeWGTQayiyUzwzG9Cf21cxU5NY4iHrDxarqjL27tmDW271nql6iM+jjHDUqFH88EOioCCf+9p80VZYZPTtY4rbkWLxg3mJ9QEBPD4Lt7vSvC+HVrZCT2IMpmSS2qXDzNagLWxbuNCRtRRDjx49xnouZtqkjxw5ypq4cD4WumDyGoLbcnRUJDRu3BgO4JYsIflRgVJoqdyYMMGSU+BGjRpBy1atKyQ4Z06f4nH0+Ozq1Svwd1xB6uoaMAczuPHjx3EfvXcsKqq6Dt24YQMYGBgK9fsUFhbykykNvIGUdZavb3\/C0om+0xhrX0dHR9wqTVh7e\/uIESU4zJnN11r+31GsJk3ic6Ix2ZDooKWJ25yqUIAx6lces9RzGWtFbDdTVeP2LCwbqC89vaRmXzh\/Ptvo5hNSkjTZygqz6im885CePl1Wgh2JCGdN2X8Y5g93794BHW1ttk3B8dOmTeOYqaSkBAm4Ih8+fAgtmjfnfrupU2EuZtrUR8kmx9AX6FTPpUuhWzdDTpPpA7KySmacBK2Khpiyb9+xkzWtZCp16JwePXrw0v+jh98X4+MxjgUI9cdIq3QqXnhlUA1Izu7UqRPHXbohlWGOCda\/BpsLVUIo7iZUe2ZklDhkFda79MxYgjJVGiPVeq6YAHoK5x6JiOC+0o9JTxw\/zjaqUYlHODGpvKEVRpk61b1eXss46SFoUdlhdWGM+cV0kSfcx1qeEs2uXbvy\/bW1tcNJk8F9RNqNG2CPY6mPDqrPCzEUVpkUVQVtaTb44R8Lmo12dnZw+fJlYZEfSuK+aNMGtm7bLix1F7kdugkTkfK1aG3n+vVr0KplK8jP\/3T+baamyO1QetOiqakJ\/8e68FPBY\/FijEU\/ClW3kduhhB8W8fRW41OAJqAJJktp6enCUrepkUOJqRjXYmPPC1V7cXdzg507dwlV1wH4Dd8Kwxhk4PHLAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu29":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>26 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>30<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Out of 240 students in a coaching centre, where every student prepares for at least one of the two exams &minus; IIT JEE and AIEEE, the number of students preparing for IIT JEE is between 75% and 85% (both inclusive), whereas the number of students preparing for AIEEE is between 35% and 45% (both inclusive). If the maximum possible and the minimum possible number of students preparing for both IIT JEE and AIEEE are denoted by A and B respectively, find the value of A + B.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>48\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>96\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>72\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>120\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu30":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>26 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>30<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">If <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">is a natural number, find the largest number which always divides the expression&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ 1) (<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ 2) (<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ 7).<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>12\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>24\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>36\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>48\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu31":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>31 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>32<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">A polynomial <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">f <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">) = <em>x<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">3<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + <em>x<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">ax <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&minus; 10 has three distinct roots, each of which is also a root of the polynomial F(<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">) = <em>x<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">4<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + <em>bx<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">3<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + 43<em>x<\/em><\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> &minus; 360<em>x<\/em> + <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">c<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">, where <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">, <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">c <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">are real numbers. If <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&lt; 0, find the value of (<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">+ <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">c<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">).<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"-456","CORRECT_ANSWER":"-456","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu32":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>31 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>32<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">If log<\/span><sub style=\"font-family: Arial;\">6<\/sub><sub style=\"font-family: Arial;\">c<\/sub><sub style=\"font-family: Arial;\">o<\/sub><sub style=\"font-family: Arial;\">s<\/sub><em><sub style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/sub><\/em><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(6sin<em>x<\/em>) = <\/span><img height=\"30\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAkAAAAdCAYAAAB41kadAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIUSURBVDhPlZPNbxJRFMVnmkDBBCgkdSN015haNzWEVd3UgivQ\/wEMW7Y2qVFMtcva1o9YdYEu2HammLCwC3WjoiFlCsiHA8u6IGGAhOmC43uXLyfSqCe5ybvn\/jLvvJc3AgbSmk1sbj5ENBpFLBZDoVgcTIARFPD74XQ6EQ6H4fV64fHMIZ\/P04ygZ0+fQBAEvP\/wkUxd78I5M4Pl5avUE1RTVaRSb8kYas7jxvz8RVqPtuPSdR2ZTAZra7dhs9kgywfkG6Dc0RHL4qGteaZyuUK+Aep2u2i1WqjVVFxaWMDs7HnWt8cQH\/4uaX+fvpj5+q0Pxe\/dxQW3G\/rpKQFcr16+IKj4vdSHZEkiIxyJoFQqIZ1Ow2w2YXHxMnq93ni7R1tbcDgcmJ62wGQyYXXVj0qlSjNDcE3TUCgUWPD6wOnLAJ2lf4M6nQ7q9Trbojax+ExIJBIIhUIIBoMTi88EfsS\/6f+DV6tVJJNJKr4eagTdj8fp1u12Oysbrbe3d2hGkJLLkRmJ3EK73aa6eYMFZp7KTkjQ4eE7+Hw+nJz85C3py+dPBCVevzk7+OPdHYKU4\/xk6FhR2CswIxC4Tv0fEH\/C56xWLC1dQbOpkWeAUgcyRFFEkN0yfxFDjaC9veeYmhKxvn5n4IxFkKr+gMhCrqxcY39IGQrLlM1mqRqNRh96sLEBi8UCl8sFK8vD18OSJBm\/AHEOQPkQ3jqXAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"9\" \/>,<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> for <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">lying in the interval <\/span><img height=\"34\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACMAAAAiCAYAAADVhWD8AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAQOSURBVFhH7ZdfTFtVHMfrtrcVhMyF6ISEdk1WZgcEDPogPpBhpGoCjQ8KkX+b\/AtbBRtneBgz6gzD6cI6x78wnPNPQpC9DIzAtoQMGLQbIYM3Xhyshg0DXRHYytd7fvdnoe7ewhxXXvwkJ73ne87t+dzTc2\/P1X1\/4QKKioqCSmlpGXy+eWiFz+eTxih9ZFxdTk4Ojhz5GAMDA4Hicrn5NO1wuVxBY2ZlZUEnjFpbv+Uum8fhw4dkmfr6Bo42j5KS4v9lFNFM5nRdHUwmE8xmM2JiYmCxWGAwGGDZtw+zs7PcKxhNZFzDw0hMTERZWRmSkpPhdDrxzI4dyMvPR1NzMxYWFrhnMJrIjI6O4rfbt3Hl8mXp2VFM2W6jEdeHhulYDU3XzCfHqpGXl4\/l5WVERETA7b7BLcqsS2ZwcAC5ublIS0tDVVUVpqenuSU01owMHD\/+Bfz+h4iNjcXsnJdyv99Pn\/9kTZlfurqg0+mwZ48Z2dnZdGyOi8Mcf7EaIzdvUt\/2nztoZp6SjuvqTsPxoQMez+\/cK5iQMuIKjIZY7NwZhcWlJcp6un+lQT797HOqq1FSXISw8HDcuzdD9ex336HzDh58n+SUCCkzPj5OX+BwfMSJTPTzuxCfkMg1ZTweDyYnJ7kmX9jY2BjXlAnInFWQuXr1Csk0NTVzIpOclCRd9dO4f9\/HycYgZlNVpqH+LMk0NDRyIpOX+x7lMzN\/cLIxBGSUfqaffvyBBm1sbOJE5q0331CVEfsUsTUYGhpSLaJ9cXGRz1ihpDjEmrk+OEiDOp1nOJGxvLAXzz63C0u8qFfT19cHm82GzMxM1SLaJyYm+IwVQsrcmZoiGZvtbU6Ahw8eQL99O\/anv8bJxhGQUVozApt0JULoUmcnvF4vKisqqN7Z2UV3SFtbG3p6erm3MkozqETIBSy4e3caqamvkIBer6fPDyoqqU38+4q6wWii+mq83jlUVlYgKioKkZGRUh8jvj51iluVWVPmb8RaaG9vx8jICCegh9c3Z5yIi9vLiYzIrRmvk6jdbqfZS0\/fT\/UvT37FvR5l3TJKzM\/P40Vpi1BzopYTmbFbt2jgEukNYzUm025pdsNU3zqeSEashf7+fq6tICR7e3sxNXWHExlxF+rDwqX2PzkJ5olkHoee7u6g9abEfyLTf+0atm7ZgpSXXg75Yqi5zMWODpqR1NRXpW3HHKfKaCpzsraWRAoKD3ASGs1kTtTUkEhLyzlO1iYgo\/R38G+54XaTyNZt21BeXo7CwkIUFBRQEXXVW3s9e+DHpfVcCxISEhAfH0\/vTNHR0YFisYj3JuW1o4mM2rZyLQIy589\/x9HmYbcfgu6A9JtarVZpr+sIlOrqY9xFO6qPHg0aMyUlBX8BuzhujGY3h6QAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"35\" \/><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;, find the value of tan<\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"><em>x<\/em>.<\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">Enter your answer accurate upto two decimal places. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"3","CORRECT_ANSWER":"3","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu33":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>33<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlh0QB4APcAAP\/\/\/8fHx7+\/v5eXl39\/f6enp9fX19\/f34eHh3h4eEBAQCAgIAAAADg4OGhoaFhYWCgoKDAwMEhISO\/v75+fn2BgYM\/Pz7e3txAQEAgICHBwcK+vr\/f394+Pj1BQUOfn5xgYGJqammxsbCoqKi4uLi0tLRsbG2NjYx4eHiEhIT8\/P21tbeDg4MrKynl5eRUVFRYWFjExMRcXFz4+PiMjI93d3UdHR4mJiVRUVA8PDwsLCwQEBOjo6IaGhmlpaXFxccPDwysrKx8fHyIiIiQkJE1NTY6OjnR0dF5eXnt7e9jY2FtbWxMTEzw8PDQ0NJWVlVVVVXd3dzIyMiwsLBQUFAUFBQwMDEZGRhoaGgoKCnp6ei8vL0pKSg0NDQ4ODqKiohkZGQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAA0QB4AAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmxADCNgpYACBn0AJFOApwADOo0gZHhCAIIGCBQwaKJiqwEFQoA+oKoDAIIIEAgMETEhKluYBChUaMFigIAECAQcqWrhAwIECDBkUaNgwtqxfkwbQLlhQgUIAkRwEdPCAIcLeD38jcyzwAASEwnFVWlhs2cFhyaAjCqiA4UEByDINDGiwIIHR0LAPWtAAQgGFvjcPIIAAoUPm2KA5dIAQoQPqsgY0sN0A\/O8EBAs0vA4twEMECs2RfkjQ+jhwCxUWDP\/gkN2sgwUIcJcHcOB8+vUuJygfD9\/g9gUd6qscgF9\/QvkQCOAfSQJE4IB6AxpkgAIe\/JbgRh9kZcGDDG0AAQHkUYgRdAVo2BAHBCxwgYcUfdBWhiQy9IEEGqCYIkMXBPgiRB0oMN2MB3GggQQI4rhQAA1g52NBBhQ3ZEQTVFBBjy9SEMGNRz5EQQMT+phABS5GCdGCI77IQQUIaGnRBB4I6eEEEpgpJkVfEuDhAQoImNFSCGiglQIZMJCXVhq85SBOFhAwFQgMFCrVA7cBQACWD1pApUUBICCBWmwl0AFRApCXGFEdOAVVAx4g8JlMFpwXAQE7HadTAaQpMEAIHjD\/mZ0ADXj3UKQSZNBAAheMSlEAGyTQQAYSiOrSBxVEMMCfCAlwnggKyBqbBdFGVCoIu16QpUYcXCAsCA5UiVKIajr0wXkjbBvbARFIa5BuxA1gq0gfDBABBAgw+9EECmBYkQEklKAuaHDqe5AAT7nWkgHcSSAnSBZE8LBFHpgwsHMNQInQBhHEOdMFCkTQoUcXNGDwRCegcDFZ\/IqbEAULeODyTBY8IN7KERnQgLsTOZACbBx40GVCMVZwskztQTD0mBEcXZEKKoRWmEIHeCCBxkcdIMHVFnHgcEgorCAZWgmBCAFzoMWYAM8JdaCBSCxk0MJfASgwcACn4pzUbr46\/8TBAvN25MILesc0QdMIIZBxeR804CZEbpHEAQwSlCXB0gOZmIB+BNRq7gKFY9RBDPkh9dNBFk4MXwBnNzSAAyZNIMMMfdOE8EGLsR0bmaUrdPlJChTQ7k1\/z6vB2x4er9AEIISe0etk26RB7wJx8AD1GnbwwMAbeIDSAQsA4DFNERfE78gvFlCtQU2lxAAARTpfUgQu81s7iXX3OH1KC8R1ukxuI4jXVDejumXJNClpwGE48KSYfAB0Awka5nx0AQ+4aHwWKZQGabAQD6DtdjD53UCmtqYLVG4gGKwIA2owEBvcQCEeHGG5NBMBgpBwTQCIHgAQeJEVDqQANlCIAjczB8GWxFAgAcThQP63vy3hQE0+FIgLFdI\/gjRxJeUTiAGVSBCPtQ8iOdCTmTRYqCAq5H0EeaD8\/zhyxMM57UiNO0D3IDIBHTBgB8gDgA8LgMaEgM8gV0RJFsVHQC7WjQfNg0gPdgAB3ETRBxxMyOvsU0SUHPF\/XDSI20SoQhYKhAEvRAgnrYg9kmRxkJk0iAJ+ALsMehIAfATCQZinLjVaEm30SyVCDBAEIayRIpRJiAMGcJIPgACJedSlQTpXSo8ULyFAOsnpbKnMHJVgCIHjSBITksuSVPGI1TwYEZLpkQ9EIJsD2aZIbjfHcCakCDEopEbAmRBqimRq3XSnbIJgso98kSH0\/AgHMMCBduoTIR4wQgN+uRATPsSgICFbPg9qkIipD50S2cDOHvLMkCgQohQ1iAeBNP8zihDAghEJZEcmgAEADDGkCCnfARrQzId8wAOPE40CQtI9A0AApkJcoHLQRsehsomgIJmeSoFKkEkKpGq20Z0FjgACJCSBAA94wE+GEroUcmQBSgAcUxEyUBeNBgMKuFT9BHCBJTAhBztoglaFUoCfZIVYy1qIOjcCPpCO1YYzBIAA7BQBMmLACTJgwhKISrTzeJUgqNwIWgL614GAkCEWsA5jHYIwmSEEA7qLyAP4w9BwVnEhGojAZiPCMXIK5IYbwcATKlDZhCyVIPyqqURqhCAdasSnsK0tQfw6kIjJkyIFcllkMdI9EGD0rxPIgbp09kaJwElcHMhARzqwhBr\/ChchErNPPz8Sx4FAAGsVcQAUXPtdgUQhp9VTwP02Qq2+UNYiDZDCcYVLq4LwUCQOBcBtK4KBHISWqRPQ7kCI+5GpOTUjH4BBS9uLEBm8hoHoLSfooqmRAEyhARQWJdr2OpKmsHQjA5hBK0NckP1NYAEHzkjxnKsRZrLYIJP0rUmGeVqMEKB1NyZINP97EoQ9liIOAEGG2wu+sqqEAyBown4hUgEqVLey2Q2wSioghdVS5AFVKG1IGfDPlBDgOhpRQB+DPBAM+EC3I6EAEQI7kSZY4S\/PxckCruBlhxRgvg0RAArClJERYKEsHxhCFrQAGghsAdAL4UIXvPAFihiA\/wrwtYgdycjpTnv606AOtahHTepSm\/rUqE61qYfArRi3ZANeYAAYxMwSVxdkBTnAwJQXQmvYbIAAefaPBa7M5mIb+9jIxggkk22RG2jQBzGhAQ1keRROQztFy5aiGR3CaWpfpAA3uMG1cRJFANAAfRSqwZrNje6FRJGPGbFBDdSNlHL7IJQaKsC4BSLuh5R73RMBghlt0G6alHvaJOo3QfTtb08CYd8U8QEZI3kTTuM73xBXeEM4vW0VEoQB3q5JuV9EbwDU4IUEb\/hAQG4RcBPEBxCfychftOwa2IABFN\/4K1NeERq80uQzl0nQU8THQvGx4+5+5dAHtHR3crrgzASOutSnEE71qlv96ljPuta3znUxBQQAOw==\" style=\"width: 209px; height: 120px;\" \/><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">In the figure above, two semicircles, with centres at P and Q, of radii 3 cm and 1 cm respectively, are drawn, sharing their bases with that of a larger semicircle, of diameter AB. The two smaller semicircles touch each other externally, while touching the larger semicircle internally. If a circle, centred at R, is drawn such that it touches to the two smaller semicircles externally, while touching the larger semicircle internally, find the radius (in cm) of the circle centred at R. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='10' Height= '29' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAkAAAAdCAYAAAB41kadAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIzSURBVDhPrZM\/TFNRFMbr0Da0dunrqCaCifgHp05N1M22o0TdMGlTrLaQqMFEogYnKGlTEvzHgDjgUprgQBux+Cc0wYXaBBfsE0jTpZOFYtISafv57vceBQwmDn7JybvvO79z37kv5+qgaSoWg9\/v3xeh4WHmmpDLeQlWqxUOh6MZ9\/v7mSPUaDRgamnB7Tt3af4pQuWNDeh0Ojx99hypVArz82nUajUCQoQ+LywQMpvNsFgsXJ9sb8f3ldVdaGoqBoPBgOjICMrlMrLZLGySVQFP7UJCxWJRW6mKhMPccXVtTYWq1SpK6+tM7uj15CShxcUvKtTbE1SOLynN1gkI9QaDhCqVigrNpd7R6Oq6jkwmg7GxF3y\/eSvAgmZPkUgYNpsNRqMRJpMJgUBQaWOLuSYktKX0VigUUCqVNEfVPuhv+jcon88jmUwikUgcGCKni8fj8Hq98Hg8B4bI\/ceetCeVTCbQ2XkZbrcbExOvNHcPNDQ4yL\/sdDrhcrm47uu7xxyhnaHzdd+gKXTt6hV6lUpVhRIzMzR+lNRJqNfr+Lm5iXRanVBCjx4+wGFlIkOhIbS2HockSfD5utFgifa5nkAAer2et2V09Ami0SgOKTufv3BxD6TNzvT0G5pCL8fH6a0oc07o8cAAjZLWk9DXpSV64uYQej+XovHh4ycCQrOzb+ktL39Toe3tX8rtkHD6zFnkcjJkWcaJtjYcOXqMBYSEZDmHcx0dPJkosNvt7AcAfgNn2x+zp5Ht2AAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='17' Height= '29' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABEAAAAdCAYAAABMr4eBAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAMCSURBVEhLtZXvL5VhGMfPaV4cNk7tcBwjzTkI0RatDm3J8UJMmxdWNG+xaZOsY+GUF8Sraql\/gMQWnR8bQq\/0hiS20A6Tw\/kxNkLzazG+3c\/13NuJY0L13a7tub7X83ye+7nv674fCfbIZDRCr9fzzC3b1BQMhkoUFhZSGI0mXgF2QUZGviBIpUJUVAx3RE1MjEMdFgalUomCggLodDpIJBJU1zymOkGWl5fw0GCgghCxceepKGhnZwdRkZHk2+0O7gK3c3PIs1rHRciDsjIyamvrkKjVIjT0DN0oSIDU1dXieX09d0S9amykZ7q6ukXI8PAwpqenqZiUqEVwcAhdH6T09OsMImVf8WP3nAjSXr6EkJDTPNtflRXlNIonT59RfmRIaek9AlRX13DnCJClpUWk6lII8Ka1jbuiDgVZXPyOs2yFNJpwzMzYueuWB+RiQjwCA1U8E1fnRmYmjeBRVRUsFgtaWlrQ3NxM4XS6PCHJyVcRERHBM+Db5CS8ZTL4+PhAKpUS7Pcwmy2ekPn5eczNzfEMWF9fZ29zwuVy7RsbGxuekOPo30CE4QjdarPZjhUOhwOS9vZ2ZLLZz8jIOFZkZWVBIizh3+r\/TOzrpiYUFd3hmVtWqxXFxcVIS0tDfn4+Bgc\/88oeSGdHB6SsgQKUgdwR9WlgAH6+vpDJvJGXlwe1Oow13gkYTWaqE0RosJKSEt6FUpyLjaOiIGHOhP0k1OwOJ3mbmz\/Z1lBCEy52NkHK9Pfh5eVFp9eVpKRdJxujoL+vD729H7ghSqNWQ37yFF0T5OvYGGZnxVY\/6GRbW1vD0NAQKsrLaS81NDSS7zGxBx1K73t62AuC6dNUqiCMjI6SfyTI6uoqO1OXMTE+jpjoaPj5yTHLNuuhIVtbW\/xKVE93F42ote3tnyHb29s02Sm6VO6IMpuMBOnsfOcJSYi\/wP507j4RlvhmdjY9UP\/iJRYWFvCxvx8B\/v5QsFhZWfGE5ObcYqfbNZ65dZd1q1wuZ8sfCoVCQfcIXQwAvwBKITNnqiXKIAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='31' Height= '29' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAB8AAAAdCAYAAABSZrcyAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAOcSURBVEhLtZddSJNRGMdn5QRF8NY7W1eCAwOrlYhOBZdepBdCuVDnx9xV5TaxDwuh1EBY4BI\/yubA1Ep0xkQxUsMuxAsFEycios5EbYo6sTm3Pb3n2XFT9sFc2w8eeM\/\/HM\/\/Ped9znMmC9ygm5sDiUQCBsM2VYKDi7nJ9Bdu3eTBhQsXwWg0UjU4OMxNJhN87OiAyMhIYLFYwA4Lg5WVFdobHBzmqrY2NC0sFEFxURGEhIT4bT40NAT5+flQUFDgMUQikdP818wMjI\/\/xOdnT5\/gi\/hjbrFYICEhAZqamkCr1XoNtwknl0n9NtfpdJCUlERb3gm4eXNzMxQXF9OWdwJuToxbW1tpyzsBN+fz+TA9PU1bAMdmM2g0Gqivr4fGxkZYWFigPR7MZdJyv8yXlpYgMTERjo+PHe2r8fE4V0xMDLDZbHx+974N+92aP3r4AActLy9TxTfUajUIhUJ8ttlskJ6WivMMD39D7c\/WFty4fg21jc1N9+ZkxRMTE3B0dEQV3ygtLcWtJVitVsjJvgOFoiJsn6BuV6G5Vjvg3twfyEqTk5NhdnaWKu6RlInRXK9f8998amoKVldXaQtgcXERzzdZsScGSGFhjPOE97F9bvO9vT0oL7cnZFxcHFY0gkqlwrLpiX5NH\/5NRoaAuUfsn5PVwVwmmZmZIBAIPEZNTQ0OJpBtraqqArlcjpN1dnaiLhaLsaS6o662BseKxWVgNttPAoG1xWQgyWqSZJ5iY2ODDndyeHgIUVFRwOFw8HuTl5ycnKS9TsglRYyVyrdUcfJfCUcKB5m4uroasrKyXE7H67pa7Fco3jC5YIPd3V3Y2dnBMDPFx2FuYQpDC1OXc3Nz8TocHByiPZ4hPzaio6PRoKSkhKp21vR61EmcFJfT0d\/\/1W5OkuY2s21ETElJAR6Ph89SqQwn8oZCocCxXV1dVLGzvv4bzzy5aJRKJTQ0NJwJUv3QvOfLZ5zg9HfJu3cXNd38PFXcQ7Z6dHTUUVLPA5qTtyBH5fQEta9eovnY2A+qBB6XhNs2GGBk5Dtc4VyG1LR0v1bkK2fMDw6MwGUKB1kxiZ6eXtoTHM6Yk\/SfZ74xiZycbHyB3j4N7Q08Ltt+wv7+HoSGXoIUfhpVAg+af+ruxkvBsO38D8Vms0J4eDhjnkqVwIPm7aoPuMUyeQWWSkKFXIZaS4tvv8f8wbHtL55XQUREBMTGxgKXy8VVV1Y+pr3BAOAfPdFsCE77KU8AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='30' Height= '29' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAB4AAAAdCAYAAAC9pNwMAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAOsSURBVEhLtZdbSFRRFIZHcxDMZgydyqx80MpwSstevGBFglQKgmYZFalYZjq+5CgqKOi7YBcLxLIEL4iaPigUyTTVeBl90Ap7yAuNKeL9nmJ\/+6zZjg3OWA3HDzaz11pnr\/9c1ln7jAQW6OzoQHJyMhYWFrlHfDYJz83Owt\/vBJycdnLP9mASXl5exssXL7DTyQkSiQSurgpMTU3zqPiYhEsePyLBhIREXI6JgYOD1Cbh4eFhqFQqxMfHWx2JiYkbwl1dXdBoNDS\/e+c2nYQtwmq1GrGxsairq7M66uvrNz9jgYT4WzYLh4eHQ6\/Xc8s6ogpPTEwgJCQES0tL3GMdUYVbW1sRGRnJra0RVTg\/Px\/Z2dncAmamp1FcXEzFlJeXj2\/f+nlEZOGoqCi0tLTQfGRkBCeOKylPUFAQdru4wNnZGa\/fvKG4ReG4q1doweTkFPf8nbm5OQQHB7OTNa65FhdHOd6+bSV7kj1\/N1dX+CqPk21RuKenB83NzVhZWeWev6PVahEREcEtoKmpESUlT7hl5HTAKdjvcKC5RWFbKCoqQnp6OrfMWVxcRENDPRwdHZGhziSfTcJra2sYGxvjlpE4dmurq6u5tYFe3wkPDw+67fvZ7+joKPn\/W1in08HX1xdubm4YGhoi3+rqKr2\/BoOB7D8RTlB4DA2sW+3bu5etVWJ+fgGSmpoaREdHU0VaG+Xl5TwNkJOTg7S0NLoCoe8KCO02LCyM5ltRVVlJ6xpeNULS39+PDrb\/bjUGBgb40g0EISGJUMVlZWVITU3lESOFhQW4m5LCLSPCbRfWVFVV215c7e3tlCQrKwuZmZkoLS3lESNnQ0MprtFoyf7F6iIy4hL5BgeHzIV1uo+sw+RRooqKCrZH\/+QRywhXLZVK4e3tzZINcq8Rg+E7jvn4kFBgYCA8PT1pXlBYSHGTsDrjPgUUij1QKtc7TjBr\/JP8iM20tbXRcV5eXtxjzszMDB4+eICkpCRkZKjNdi0S\/vL5MyW4fuOmqWk8f\/aMfCqV5XdzndzcXNTW1nLr3yHhbqEqz59HX99Xcq4jddgBP\/+T3BIXq8X1qbeXrjjlnnm1ioVFYaHhn\/T3g\/MuGQZ5kxCbTcJCQQSwZm5nZw\/t+w\/cKz5mwl\/7+nDo4AHsc3dn3aibe7cHk\/A79oUpl8tw5uw5jI+Pc+\/2QcKz7N\/DHoUCh48cZd\/FP1gTnydxYUyzz5ftgISfPimhCpbJZLTryOVy07hw4SIdKC7Ab0An++ymtDyvAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu34":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>34<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>At a certain school, the Class X has four sections \u2212 A, B, C and D. A committee of students needs to be formed by selecting exactly two representatives from each of the four sections. If each section has four representatives, comprising two boys and two girls, and the committee must comprise four boys and four girls, in how many ways can the committee be formed?\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"454","CORRECT_ANSWER":"454","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"}}